# Mujtaba Iqbal

# Front-End Web Developer

Highly motivated Web Developer with focus on front-end and userexperience. Deep knowledge in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, and modern JavaScript libraries and frameworks such as React.js, AngularJS 2.0+, and Node.js. Working knowledge in SASS, LESS, Git, and Bootstrap.

mujtaba.iq@gmail.com

(718) 450-1430

Jamaica, NY

mujtaba718.github.io/Mujtaba\_Iqbal\_CV

github.com/Mujtaba718 (7)

## WORK EXPERIENCE

# Front-End Web Developer X Gallery

02/2018 - Present

Maintain and update website to ensure an appealing and user friendly experience.

#### Responsibilites

- Design the layout of website from provided design concepts using standard HTML5 and CSS3 practices.
- Inspect code to ensure that it is properly structured, meets industry standards, and is compatible with all browsers and devices.
- Optimize website for maximum speed.

Contact: Lisa DuBois - (504) 577-1268

#### Math Tutor

# Varsity Tutors

07/2017 - Present

New York, NY

Harlem, NY

Provide one-on-one tutoring to students seeking assistance in multiple areas of math.

#### Responsibilities

- Prepare daily lesson plans to evaluate student performance and provide feedback for improvement.
- Assist students with their daily homeworks and assignments.
- Help students prepare for their Regents, SATs, ACTs, and college placement exams.

# **EDUCATION**

# **Bachelor of Science, Applied Mathematics** The City College of New York

08/2012 - 07/2017

Harlem, NY

#### Courses

 Calculus I, II, III, Discrete Mathematics, Linear Algebra, Probability and Statistics, Numerical Analysis.

# **Pro-Tek Consulting** Web Development Boot Camp

08/2017 - 01/2018

Oueens, NY

#### Description

- Developed skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (React.js, jQuery, AngularJS, Node.js), and other technologies.
- Completed daily tasks and weekly projects gaining experience in responsive design, cross-browser compatibility, and deployment.
- Collaborated with camp members by using Git and other version control software.

## SKILLS

Dependable

Adaptable

**Team Oriented** 

## **PROJECTS**

#### Portfolio Website 🗷

- Used clean and semantic HTML5 markup.
- Utilized CSS3 transitions for striking effects.
- Used fluid layout and media queries to make the site adjust to an screen size.
- Used gulp plugins to optimize images and files for fast load time.
- Used modern ES6+ syntax.

### Clear View Escapes 🗷

- Developed a mobile-first travel agency website.
- Used semantic HTML5 markup and BEM naming convention.
- Used CSS3 transitions to make striking effects.
- Responsive layout. Adjusts to any screen size.
- Used gulp plugins to optimize images and files for fast load time.
- Leveraged jQuery libraries such as smooth-scroll and waypoints to animate page on scroll.

#### Omnifood

- Developed a food delivery website.
- Used HTML5 and CSS3 best practices.
- Responsive layout. Adjusts to any screen size.
- Optimized images and files for fast load time.
- Leveraged ¡Query libraries and CSS3 transitions to make beautiful animations.

## Everyday Things 🔀

- Responsive website for everyday products.
- Used HTML5 and CSS3 best practices.
- Utilized CSS3 transitions to animate website on scroll.
- Made a fully functioning drop down menu.

# **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

HTML5 CSS3

Full Professional Proficiency Full Professional Proficiency

JavaScript

Professional Working Proficiency

Professional Working Proficiency

Professional Working Proficiency

Professional Working Proficiency

**AngularJS** 

Professional Working Proficiency

Node.is

Professional Working Proficiency

Professional Working Proficiency

Professional Working Proficiency